SUDHANSHU KULKARNI Software Developer

simplysudhanshu.github.io @ sudhanshu.kulkarni.13@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/sudhanshu-kulkarni **1** +(1) 609-721 1446

github.com/simplysudhanshu San Francisco, CA

An earnest Software Developer bringing deep research and application-oriented profile to the table. My years of experience ensure clean, efficient software, and I'm currently diving headfirst (coffee in hand!) into the exciting worlds of HPC and Quantum Computing.



EXPERIENCE

11/2022 - 05/2024

(1 yr, 7 mos)

Graduate Research Assistantship - SAN FRANCISCO STATE UNIVERSITY, San Francisco, CA

- Formulated feasibility studies on performing scalable FFT computations "in situ" on HPC platforms leveraging CPU, GPU & Quantum hardware to support scientific analysis workloads in exascale NERSC projects like WarpX.
- Collaborated with scientists at the LBNL supercomputing facility to conduct extended research on Perlmutter & CORI, achieving a minimum of 10x speedup in computation time compared to traditional methods. Devised a novel FFT numerical library in C++ for distributed-memory massively parallel processing architecture.

05/2023 - 08/2023

SDE Intern - AMAZON WEB SERVICES (AWS), Seattle, WA

(3 mos)

- Prototyped a robust monitoring service to ensure timely capturing of critical metrics to enhance service reliability by at least 10% after full-fledged deployment on thousands of live AWS servers worldwide as a part of the AWS CloudFront CDN services' platform team.
- Curated live dashboards to provide real-time visibility into at least 70% of all the agents running on servers, empowering the team to actively maintain reliability and diagnose potential issues.

08/2020 - 07/2022

Software Engineer - ELASTICRUN, Pune, IN

(2 yrs)

- Engineered an enterprise-grade ERP platform on the Frappe framework, streamlining logistics and B2B eCommerce processes, while single-handedly contributing to 20% of the 'Velocity' segment's development workload.
- Refined ground-level operational efficiency by executing heavy Python-based server-side development, and business focused PWAs using Flutter and SvelteJS in an agile software development environment.
- Orchestrated an automated testing framework and handled bi-weekly live software deployments with the DevOps team based on Kubernetes and GitLab-based CI/CD pipelines, boosting deployment rate and reliability by ≈15%.

03/2018 - 07/2018

(4 mos)

IoT Specialist Intern - SCMIND LLC, Princeton, NJ

Designed and implemented low-level Python solution for IoT-enabled supply chain machinery firmware on singleboard microprocessors, enabling an 85% decline in unplanned downtime through real-time performance monitoring and sensor-based anomaly detection integrated via cloud pipeline feeding a global PowerBI dashboard.

</> Technical Proficiency

Languages Frameworks Python, C/C++, Java, CUDA, TypeScript, Javascript, SQL, R, HTML/CSS, bash.

SENSEI, Qiskit, cuQuantum, Frappe, Django, Flask, SvelteJS, React, Node.js, MySQL, NoSQL, Redis, Helm.

Git, Tensorflow, PyTorch, Keras, SciPy/NumPy, MPI/OpenMP, Linux, AWS, GCP, Azure, Docker/Kubernetes, ElasticSearch, nginx, REST, Linux, PowerBI, Jira.



EDUCATION

Tools

MS - COMPUTER SCIENCE, San Francisco State University

High-Performance Computing, Quantum Computing, Artificial Intelligence, Software Engineering, Advanced Algorithms

2020

BE - COMPUTER ENGINEERING, International Institute of Information Technology (SPPU)

Machine Learning, Data Mining and Analytics, Cloud Computing, Databases, Data Structures

NOTABLE EXPERIENCES AND PUBLICATIONS

- An integral member of the Early-Career Conference Review Board for the ISAV workshop at The Super-Computing conference (SC23), tasked with a technical assessment of submitted research papers and complimented it with a noteworthy lightning talk on Scalable FFT Peer Reviewed Abstract from the conference: https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.01843 %
- Contributor to the Open Source SENSEI Project as a new FFT analysis backed endpoint.
- Quantified and benchmarked Quantum Encoding models as part of Master's Thesis and pioneered research on identifying challenges and computational overheads to optimize Hybrid Classical-Quantum interfacing advancing the field of practical quantum computing. Thesis % | GitHub %
- Successfully earned IBM Quantum Challenge 2024 Achievement for performing utility-scale quantum experiments. %
- Architected a GIS project to perform analysis on multi-spectral & temporal satellite data employing Deep Learning Networks & signalmatching algorithms yielding over 80% accuracy and collaborated with scientists from ISRO, NRSC & Geospatial Design Labs. %